Daniel Mori

Full Stack Developer

Highly skilled **Full Stack Developer** with over **8 years of experience** designing and implementing complex software solutions. Proficient in a wide range of programming languages and frameworks, including **React, Angular, Node.js**. Strong problem-solving and analytical skills, with a passion for learning new technologies and keeping up with industry trends.

CONTACT

daniel.morious@gmail.com

Stuttgart, Germany

EDUCATION

- Master of Computer Science, University of Tokyo, 2012-2015
- Bachelor of Computer Science, Nagoya University, 2008-2012
- Programming Coursework: Computer Programming, Algorithms & Data Structures, Operating Systems, Networks

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Programming languages: JavaScript(6), TypeScript(3), Python(2), Ruby(1)
- Frameworks / Libraries: React(5), Vue(1), Node.js(5), Ruby on Rails(1), Django(2), Flask(1)
- Databases / Tools: MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, DynamoDB
- Cloud services: AWS(4), Azure(1), Google Cloud Platform(2)
- Tools: Git, Jira, Confluence, Docker, Kubernetes, Terraform, CircleCl

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Developer

TeamViewer

Jun 2021 - Present

- Implemented efficient & scalable front-end architectures, resulting in improved page load times and reduced bounce rates.
- Optimized site performance by implementing industry best practices, resulting in increased user satisfaction & retention.
- Adopted new technologies, resulting in 30% increase in development efficiency & 20% improvement in product quality.
- Redesigned project architecture by micro-frontend and mid-tier microservices in React.js and Node.js

<u>Leveraged knowledge</u> in React, Next.js, TypeScript, React Hooks, Material UI, Jest, Cypress, Node.js, Feathers.js, REST APIs, GraphQL, PostgreSQL, Redis, Docker, AWS

Full Stack Developer

Capgemini

Apr 2016 - Jun 2021

- Developed & launched a web application that increased user engagement by 30%, resulting in a 10% increase in revenue.
- Optimized database queries resulting in a 30% reduction in query time, improving site performance and user experience.
- Designed & developed a REST API that reduced server response time by 20%, improving site performance and scalability.
- Converted high-fidelity mockups into usable websites with HTML, JavaScript, AJAX, and JSON coding ensuring the pixel perfectness of 100%.

<u>Leveraged knowledge</u> in React, Vue, JavaScript, Python, Django, Flask, MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Ruby on Rails, Google Cloud Platform

Web Developer

NimbusWorks

Aug 2014 - Mar 2016

- Successfully migrated a legacy PHP application to a modern framework, reducing maintenance time and saving the company budget.
- Developed and deployed a Node.js web application reducing deployment time by 40%, and improving site availability and scalability.

Leveraged knowledge in PHP, Laravel, Node.js Express.js, MySQL, PostgreSQL

CERTIFICATIONS

- AWS Certified Developer Associate
- MongoDB Certified Developer, Associate Level
- Microsoft Certified: Azure Developer Associate
- React Nanodegree program from Udacity